

 $\succ$ 

daniel@danieljlum.com

(44

(415)336-7925



Lake Oswego, United States



April 02, 1980



danieljlum.com

#### in

linkedin.com/in/daniel-lum-381762152

### **OTHER SKILLS**

Hardware Management

Microsoft Office

Windows Servers

Virtual Environments

Cloud Computing

Web Development

CMS

Google Analytics

Google Search Console

Adobe Creative Cloud

Cisco

SEO

WordPress

Joomla

# **Daniel Lum**

#### Network Administrator

Hello, I've been a Network Administrator for Salty's Waterfront Seafood Grills for 8 years. I successfully built, secured and managed the entire network infrastructure spanning between 3 separate locations with an emphasis around security and network procedures. I know I could transform your companies network into a secure & efficient environment. If you're interested, I hope you'll also check out my LinkedIn portfolio to see more of what I can do for you.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Network Administrator**

#### Salty's Waterfront Seafood Grills 🗷

01/2012 - Present

A family owned Waterfront Seafood Restaurant serving Seattle and Portland for more than 25 years.

Achievements/Tasks

- Windows Server administration and maintenance including Active Directory and Group Policy.
- Configure end user devices such as laptops/desktops, printers, and shared office equipment.
- □ Configure, test and troubleshot routers, firewalls, LAN/WAN/VLAN/Wireless network.
- Manage all stages of website creations, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management of Web site.
- Establish design guidelines, standards, and best practices with concern to Web Development while
  maintaining the appearance of our website by enforcing content standards.
- Manage web applications and user interface for various clients. Projects included setting the backend of e-commerce website using Ecwid/Woocommerce that created a global presence.
- Work in tandem with our marketing team regarding analytics, SEO, collateral development and email campaigns using Salesforce.
- Built and manage Aloha POS infrastructure for all 3 locations while integrating with 3rd party applications and API's.
- Increased website sales 150% for 2014 vs. 2020, and successfully raised Website sales year over year consistently by 25%.
- Increased website traffic year over year since 2014 by 30% to 50%.

Contact: Chris Darst (General Manager) – (206)937-1600

# **Sole Proprietor**

#### DL Web Design & Information Services

01/2015 – Present

Portland Oregon

Portland, OR

Offering web design and development solutions for the last 5 years with and emphasis on customer satisfaction.

Achievements/Tasks

- Manage all stages of website creations for clientele, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management of websites. Completed over 12 projects representing over 300 employees.
- □ Implement web software such as traffic analyzers, banner programs and onsite SEO.
- Improve coding of CSS and JavaScript to enhance functionality and user experience.
- Migrate hosting servers with detailed plans including simulating, testing and setting up complex configurations.
- Maintain existing sites based on custom HTML, WordPress, Joomla and Squarespace.

Contact: Daniel Lum - (415)336-7925

#### OTHER SKILLS

Squarespace

HTML5

PHP

Low Voltage

TCP/IP

**JavaScript** 

SonicWall

WatchGaurd

#### **LANGUAGES**

#### English

Full Professional Proficiency

#### Spanish

Limited Working Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

My Family

Jiu-Jitsu

My Animals

Gaming

Flying Planes

Music

Cooking

Marketing

Sports

Soccer

Learning languages

Playing Drums

Coding

Golfing

**Futsol** 

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Information Technology Field Technician Sentinel Tech, LLC

01/2015 - Present

Portland OR

Portland based IT company offering networking, data security, web development, server setup, email configuration & IT maintenance services.

Achievements/Tasks

- Diagnose, repair and maintain hardware and software components to ensure the smooth running of computer and network systems.
- Install and configure hardware and software components to ensure usability.
- Provide support to users by being the first point of contact for error reporting.
- Identify and solve any problems that arise with computer networks and systems.
- Assist in network design and implementation.

Contact: Kyle Brown - (503)957-0539

# Information Technology Field Technician

#### Colabra Information Systems

01/2018 - Present

Portland Oregon Portland based IT company offering networking, data security, web development, server setup, email configuration &

IT maintenance services. Achievements/Tasks

Task information available upon request.

Contact: Daren Stensrud - (503)703-4308

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Honor Roll/Deans List Spring 2013

Honor Roll/Presidents List Fall 2013

Honor Roll/Presidents List Winter 2014 - Fall 2014

Honor Roll/Deans List Spring 2015

Honor Roll/Deans List Fall 2016 - Fall 2017

Graduated with AA in Network Administration (06/2013 – 06/2017)

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

www.p5pro.com (06/2013 – Present) 🗹

P5 Productions is an apparel imprinting and embroidery company that required an update to their E-commerce, SEO platform, and also the ability to communicate with their new and existing clients via sales campaigns.

www.saltys.com (01/2014 – Present)

Salty's Waterfront Seafood Grills is a Restaurant group serving the Pacific North West for the last 27 years. Their website required an SEO and secure e-commerce platform while adhering to strict branding guidelines and protocols through design.

www.unimec.com (01/2015 – 03/2015) 🗹

 Universal Mechanical Services provides HVAC solutions in Washington State. They requested a more updated look to their website while maintaining functionality and the ability to be responsive.

www.restituteconstruction.com (03/2019 – 06/2019)

Restitute Construction is a boutique construction company based in the PNW. They required a design update along with an SEO and analytics tracking platform.

www.esquelatheband.com (05/2019 – 07/2019) 🗹

Esquela the Band required a transfer from WordPress to Squarespace due to multiple SQL injections and the inability to update an outdated template.

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

www.livestockmusic.com (04/2020 - 06/2020) 🗹

- Livestock Music required an updated look and feel to their site while offering streaming and downloadable content.
- -- More Projects Available Upon Request

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Network Administration**South Seattle College

06/2013 - 06/2017

#### Courses

- Computing Technology
- Computer Programming
- Web Development
- Virtualization and the Cloud
- Cisco (4 levels)

Seattle, Wa | GPA of 3.9

- Database Management
- Operating Systems (Linux & Windows)
- PC Hardware and Local Area Networks
- Network Security & Wireless Communications
- Research and Customer Service